Estelle Ishigo papers, 1941-1957
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Ishigo papers., 1941-1957.; 8.5 linear ft.
  - Artwork at the Relocation Camp., 1942-1945 & 1954.; (6.5 linear ft.)
    - Dust Storm, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, September 4, 1942.., Date Created: ">September 4, 1942.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 26 x 31 cm.) (Box 719)
      Impressionistic watercolor painting depicting people caught in a dust storm outside of Heart Mountain Relocation Center. Handwritten text appears on the bottom left corner of the painting: "Sept. 4 -42. 4:30 P.M. Dust Storm. Japanese Relocation Center, Heart Mt. Wyoming."
    - Japanese Americans, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 26 x 31 cm.) (Box 719)
      Watercolor painting depicting Japanese Americans in Heart Mountain Relocation Center
    - Japanese American internees, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: ">May 1942.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 33 x 28 cm.) (Box 719)
      Watercolor painting depicting Japanese Americans outside of barracks in Heart Mountain Relocation Center
    - At home at Heart Mountain., Date Created: December 1942.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 23 x 31 cm.) (Box 719)
      Watercolor painting depicting a Japanese American family sitting at a table inside of their barrack in Heart Mountain Relocation Center. Handwritten text appears at the bottom of the painting: "Home. Heart Mt. Wyo. Dec. 42." Signed, "Estelle Ishigo."
    - Boys with kite., Date Created: "> September 1944.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 31 x 46 cm.) (Box 719)
      Watercolor painting depicting two Japanese American boys with their kite caught in barbed wire
    - Camp Life, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, ca. 1942.., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 26 x 31 cm.) (Box 719)
      Watercolor painting depicting people standing outside of barracks in Heart Mountain Relocation Center. In the foreground is a woman carrying a pail
    - Memorial Day, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, May 1944.., Date Created: May 1944.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 31 x 46 cm.) (Box 719)
      Handpainted on bottom left corner: "Memorial Day. Heart Mt. Estelle Ishigo, 5-44." Watercolor painting of a landscape surrounding the barracks of Heart Mountain Relocation Center. People are depicted standing in lines holding umbrellas
    - Windstorm in Heart Mountain Cemetery, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, 1944.., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 25 x 35 cm.) (Box 719)
      Pencil drawing depicting a Japanese American adult and child walking through a cemetery during a windstorm
    - Three Drawings of Camp Life, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, 1942-1945..
      - The block meetings., 1942.; Date Created: [between 1942 and 1945].; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 20 cm.) (Box 719)
        Pencil drawing depicting a group of Japanese Americans convened for a meeting inside of a barrack Handwritten title on bottom left corner of paper This drawing is mounted on board with two other drawings, together they are titled "Three Drawings of Camp Life." The other two drawings are "Gangs Formed" and "Sundays"
      - Gangs formed., 1942.; Date Created: [between 1942 and 1945].; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 20 cm.); (Handwritten title on bottom right corner of paper (Box 719)
        Pencil drawing depicting a group of Japanese American kids standing outside. Two appear to be fighting This drawing is mounted on board with two other drawings, together they are titled "Three Drawings of Camp Life." The other two drawings are "The Block Meetings" and "Sundays"
      - Sundays., 1942.; Date Created: [between 1942 and 1945].; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 15 x 25 cm.); (Handwritten title on bottom left corner of paper) (Box 719)
        Pencil drawing depicting a group of Japanese Americans playing baseball. This drawing is mounted on board with two other drawings, together they are titled "Three Drawings of Camp Life." The other two drawings are "Gangs Formed" and "The Block Meetings"
    - Three Views of Traveling to Camp, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, 1942..
      - Line up for winter clothing., Date Created: September 1942.; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 14 x 22 cm.) (Box 719)
        Black and white drawing of Japanese Americans lined up outside waiting to enter a barrack. Title and date are handwritten on bottom left of drawing.
      - Bus., Date Created: November 10, 1945.; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 25 cm.) (Box 719)
        Black and white drawing of what appears to be the inside of a bus transporting Japanese Americans to Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - The road to Heart Mountain., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 9 x 29 cm.) (Box 719)
        Black and white pencil sketch of buses driving on a long winding road to Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
    - Two Views.
      - Boarding the truck to leave Heart Mountain., Date Created: May 10, 1942.; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 22 x 28 cm.) (Box 719)
        Black and white drawing depicting a large group of Japanese Americans with suitcases and bags waiting to board a truck. Handwritten on bottom left corner of drawing: "7AM, May 10, 1942."
      - The last of Heart Mountain., Date Created: November 9, 1945.; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 22 x 35 cm.) (Box 719)
        Black and white drawing depicting Japanese Americans boarding a train at night to leave Heart Mountain Relocation Center.